<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on I&#39;m Kernel Dev</title>
        <link>https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on I&#39;m Kernel Dev</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alwin Doss&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 17:15:04 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>How to Set Up Static IP on Freebsd</title>
            <link>https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/freebsd/how-to-set-up-staticip-on-freebsd/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 17:15:04 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/freebsd/how-to-set-up-staticip-on-freebsd/</guid>
            <description>Perhaps some context As a brand new user of FreeBSD I tried to install it on my laptop, that perhaps was a grave mistake because I managed to crash my system. I cannot fault FreeBSD or it&amp;rsquo;s documentation because they are thorough. I shot my own foot when I ventured out and tried installing it thinking I can wing it. Was I wrong? Absolutely!
I had to eventually resort to familiarity of Ubuntu.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="perhaps-some-context">Perhaps some context</h2>
<p>As a brand new user of FreeBSD I tried to install it on my laptop, that perhaps was a grave mistake because I managed to crash my system. I cannot fault FreeBSD or it&rsquo;s documentation because they are thorough. I shot my own foot when I ventured out and tried installing it thinking I can wing it. Was I wrong? Absolutely!</p>
<p>I had to eventually resort to familiarity of Ubuntu.
I didn&rsquo;t give up on the idea on getting started on FreeBSD therefore this time I followed the documentation and installed it as a host on Virtualbox. When installing I chose the DHCP configuration for my network.</p>
<p>After getting familiar with how to get around the system, still in the first week of exploring I reached a point where I was tired of first finding out what the IP address of my host was which was assigned by my router and then login to it through the shell. Perhaps I reached this point of frustration because I have configured all my systems with Static IP and I know them.</p>
<p>So I started on my journey to setup my FreeBSD host with a static IP. This post is in noway a replacement of FreeBSD Handbook or any other official documentation(I am not aware of any other than the Handbook). It is my attempt at helping a newcomer in setting up a static IP. you could consider this a complimentary document to the Handbook. Though the Handbook is well writted it can be dauting for a newbie to find what he is looking for.</p>
<h2 id="so-how-do-you-set-up-static-ip-on-freebsd">So how do you set up static IP on FreeBSD</h2>
<p>The configuration to edit the network lives in a file call <code>/etc/rc.conf</code></p>
<p><strong>DHCP configuration looks as follows</strong></p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-Bash" data-lang="Bash">hostname<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;name.example.com&#34;</span>
ifconfig_em0<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;DHCP&#34;</span>
</code></pre></div><p><strong>For static IP change the configuration as follows</strong></p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-Bash" data-lang="Bash">hostname<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;name.example.com&#34;</span>
ifconfig_em0<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;inet 192.168.1.12 netmask 255.255.255.0&#34;</span>
defaultrouter<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;192.168.1.1&#34;</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Here, in both DHCP and Static IP configuration the second line <code>ifconfig_em0</code> can change according to your device.
<code>em0</code> in my system refers to a networking device. To find out which one is in use in your system run <code>ifconfig</code> and choose the device that is apt for you. Eventually the second line will look like this <code>ifconfi_xxx</code>, here <code>xxx</code> will be replaced by the device you are working with.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Though this post talks about <code>how to setup static IP in FreeBSD</code> in my opinion nothing can replace the FreeBSD Handbook. However like I said earlier it can be a daunting task for a newbie to find the information he or she is looking for. So you can find the static IP configuration information in the Handbook in section <a href="https://www.freebsd.org/doc/handbook/config-network-setup.html">11.5.2. Configuring the Network Card</a>.</p>
<p>Do let me know if this helped you in anyway, it will only encourage me to write more such posts. If you have comments please do reach out to me. I would like to listen and improve.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
