<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on I&#39;m Kernel Dev</title>
        <link>https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on I&#39;m Kernel Dev</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alwin Doss&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 18:02:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>I am a Kernel Developer</title>
            <link>https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/about/me/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 18:02:48 +0530</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://www.imkernel.dev/posts/about/me/</guid>
            <description>I do many things like managing teams, programs but at heart I am a software engineer who always aspired to be a Kernel Developer.
Am I a Kernel Developer now? No, not at all, not even close! The day I become a Kernel Developer is when I will reveal my true identity until such a point I would like to operate under this pseudo-name imkernel. This site is a reflection of what I want to be eventually as a programmer.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I do many things like managing teams, programs but at heart I am a software engineer who always aspired to be a Kernel Developer.</p>
<p>Am I a Kernel Developer now? No, not at all, not even close!
The day I become a Kernel Developer is when I will reveal my true identity until such a point I would like to operate under this pseudo-name <code>imkernel</code>. This <a href="https://www.imkernel.dev">site</a> is a reflection of what I want to be eventually as a programmer.</p>
<p>Whenever I lauch this website I want to remind myself that I am a Kernel Developer and I truly believe that when I do that I will focus my attention on what I want to be and will be that one day.</p>
<p>I have chosen FreeBSD as the OS of choice to learn Operating Systems or to even contribute to. Currently I am learning about the Operating Systems by reading this book <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_Systems:_Design_and_Implementation">Operating Systems: Design and Implementation</a> by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_S._Tanenbaum">Andrew S. Tanenbaum</a></p>
<p>If you have any suggestions or comments do reach out to me on all the social media platforms. You can find the link to them in the footer if I am not wrong</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
